OLIVIA HARTWIG (THEY/THEM)

161 North Winooski Avenue, Apt #3, Burlington, VT 05401 | <u>oliviahartwig@gmail.com</u> | 716.531.2318 LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/oliviahartwig/</u> | Personal Portfolio: oliviahartwig.com

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Ten years experience as a ceramic artist, scientist, educator, and operations manager have honed my innate creative instincts into a sharp technical eye, an honest communication style, and a deep delight for the creation and implementation of systems. These skills equip me with a unique perspective as a newly minted web developer — one who's affable and hard-working nature shines brightest when part of a team. I am a natural community builder who leads from within by developing and empowering individual team members, often through the lens of social justice (e.g. identity, privilege, restorative practices), creating cultures where everyone feels valued and wants to contribute.

Languages	CSS HTML JavaScript Python PHP (basic)
	React Express Node.js Firebase Bootstrap
	Git GitHub Heroku Postman
	VS Code WordPress
	Marketing & Content Creation Photoshop Illustrator InDesign
Other Technical Skills	Ceramics Resin Casting TTRPGs Mandolin

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Phantom Theater Warren, VT Nov 2020 – present

Sometimes funky, occasionally shocking, always entertaining, not to be missed! (www.phantomtheatre.org)

Developer – Capstone Project, Burlington Code Academy

Member of a team tasked with developing a user friendly, dynamic, community-focused web application to store and present media in a unified layout, easily manage new artist information, automate updates across the site, and maintain the vibe of a rural Vermont theater on a summer evening. Conduct weekly client meetings to review and refine.

- Work on the website styling by materializing client's aesthetic requests using React, CSS3, and Bootstrap
- Served as front end project manager and communications manager and coded media queries for mobile-first development
- Technology used included a FERN Stack (Firebase, Express, React, Node.js), Bootstrap, CSS3, Nodemailer, and GitHub

University of Vermont Burlington, VT May 2016 – present

Two UVM organizations. One, a multi-generational pottery studio open to the public and university members offering 12-week classes and open memberships. The other, an Arts and Creativity Learning Community Team within Residential Life.

Program Coordinator, Residential Life...... Jan 2021 – present Studio Manager, Pottery Co-Op...... May 2017 – Sep 2020

Student Life Professional, Residential Life May 2017 – Sep 2020

Summer Assistant, Pottery Co-OpSummer 2016

As a <u>Program Coordinator</u>, manage communications and create content for learning community's social media, create programming for students living on- and off-campus during a global pandemic, and supervise 14 students. As a <u>Studio Manager</u>, developed 12-week curriculum each semester, supervised 15 student employees and 20 teachers and teacher assistants, managed space for 200 studio users, taught ceramics at various skill levels, and created new safety systems in accordance with OSHA regulations. As a <u>Student Life Professional</u>, participated in Residential Life events and led diversity and multi-cultural inclusion trainings. As a <u>Summer Assistant</u>, supervised two employees, maintained equipment and inventory, and upheld community standards. Awarded the Above and Beyond Award (2018/2019) for a number of successful initiatives:

- Improved studio ease-of-use and allowed more employee autonomy by streamlining studio operations
- Wrote and enacted new studio safety policies and documentation of hazardous materials resulting in improved conditions;
 received support and approval by Risk Management Office
- · Increased revenue by expanding programming through more classes and workshops and recruiting instructors
- Worked with insurance and physical plant on campus to restore kiln room equipment and materials due to water damage

O'twig Co. Burlington, VT Jul 2016 – Dec 2020

Handmade ceramics shipped internationally, "Happy Pots for Happy Homes." (www.etsy.com/shop/otwigco)

Owner and Operator

Created clay, glaze, and wares and managed all aspects of business including marketing and sales and completed client commissions.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

<u>Vermont Mold Co.</u> Burlington, VT Jul 2016 – Aug 2018

Provided plaster slip casting molds and workshops for Vermont ceramicists.

Owner and Operator

Worked independently to solicit customers, met with clients to create large and medium scale plaster molds, and led workshops.

EARLIER ARTS-RELATED EXPERIENCE
Glaze Technician
Caster, Trimmer
Assistant Director, Director
Education
 Bachelor of Fine Arts
CERTIFICATIONS
Full Stack Web Development Certificate (480+ hours) Burlington Code Academy, Burlington, VT
Certificate of Completion
 Worldwide Opportunities on Organic Farms (WWOOF) Europe